{
    "id": "22fcffb6d24341218e3b982d35c4eabc",
    "title": "Tenses Worksheet",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I will wait here until you …………………..",
            "description": "When both clauses refer to future, use a simple future in the main clause and simple present in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "return",
                "will return",
                "returned"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3ac85f67bfe94052915e9e9a3c23ac42"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I knew that you were coming, I ……………………….. dinner.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will prepare",
                "would prepare",
                "can prepare"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "92a5bd76cd314129af295e791d7126ff"
        },
        {
            "question": "If they had paid heed to the warning signs, this …………………………..",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect in the if-clause and would + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will not happen",
                "would not happen",
                "would not have happened"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ebe98464cbd9450eb58db52bff158383"
        },
        {
            "question": "It took me quite sometime to get used to ………………………… in a large city.",
            "description": "The to in used to is a preposition. A verb used after a preposition should be in its ing form. ",
            "answers": [
                "live",
                "living"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e077f56e02034f32ab0f7ae31ebe2c80"
        },
        {
            "question": "What she said ………………………. no sense to me.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "made",
                "has made",
                "will make"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "cbc555b82cf84c9e81ee0732a4c01112"
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me if I ………………………. him some money.",
            "description": "'Can you lend me some money?' he asked. He asked if I could lend him some money. Can in direct speech becomes could in indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "can lend",
                "could lend",
                "will lend"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f0ca6e55255e4bd2887385b6c1c38277"
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited and waited but he …………………… come.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the simple past, use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "doesn't come",
                "didn't come",
                "hadn't come"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "fbe8ad13cc2942838607e57a3316d935"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. to anybody.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to refer to time up to now. ",
            "answers": [
                "never apologized",
                "had never apologized",
                "have never apologized"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "eb603471123f4c079f4c2efb7a05b224"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will give you a call when I …………………….. ready.",
            "description": "When both clauses refer to future, use a simple future in the main clause and simple present in the subordinate clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "will be",
                "would be"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f36d122680f840dc88a1fea3db399c8d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked him where he ……………………….. the previous day.",
            "description": "I asked him, 'Where were you yesterday?' I asked him where he had been the previous day. Simple past in the direct speech becomes past perfect in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "had been",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f693838a62234670af3c6a231e41148e"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is time you ……………………… a job.",
            "description": "Use a simple past after it is time.",
            "answers": [
                "find",
                "found",
                "had found"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9a89cb955a674ad493017c7c2f5aa475"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would rather you ………………………… home now.",
            "description": "Use a simple past after would rather. ",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "will go",
                "went",
                "had gone"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "71783856109a439cb5f0a94443d61925"
        }
    ]
}